squaremeal.co.uk 2019-04-30

# Privacy and Cookie Policy - SquareMeal

This privacy policy (the "Policy") describes how and why Monomax Ltd and its Subsidiaries ("we", "our", "us") obtain, store and process data which can identify you. We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our users whilst we provide the personalised and valuable services (the "Services") via our printed publications, our websites (www.squaremeal.co.uk and www.venuesandevents.co.uk) our mobile applications, our social media accounts and our events (all here referred to as the "Sites").

By visiting or using our Sites, to the extent permitted by applicable law and our terms, you are consenting to us gathering and processing information about you in accordance with this Policy, although consent may not be required for all of the elements described in this Policy.

Third parties (such as restaurants at which you may make reservations, credit card companies, social networks that you use in connection with our Sites) may also collect, use, and share information about you. This Policy does not cover such third parties or their services and we do not take any responsibility for how such third parties may use any information they collect. For information about third-party privacy practices, please consult with them directly.

### Information we collect

**Personal Information**  
By visiting or using our Sites, we may collect the following categories of personal information (" **Personal Information** ") you provide to us: name; email address; postal address; phone numbers (including your mobile phone number); billing information; survey responses; demographics; city of residence; your restaurant reservation details; favourite restaurants; searches; sites or restaurant pages visited; special restaurant requests; dining activity (e.g., frequency, restaurants, restaurant type, cancelations, no-shows); dining preferences; marketing responses; account settings; Replies to invitations to various events and attendance at these events; passwords; information about events you are planning and/or have planned; enquires/communications directly to restaurants and venues via our Sites; contact information of people you add to, or notify of, your restaurant reservations through our Sites; customer support and other requests you make through our Sites; restaurant reviews and other information you provide on our Sites; and other information you may provide about yourself or others to our Sites or to which you provide us with access via third-party platforms. 

This personal information (excluding credit card details) will be stored together with any additional information you may provide to us from time to time, and will be used to provide you with the Services and Services associated with them.

Please note that if you choose to write a restaurant review on the Site you may disclose personal information about yourself to other users. If you do so this is at your own risk.

**Device Information**  
When you visit our Sites, some information is automatically collected from devices (e.g., mobile, computer, laptop, tablet) used to visit or use our Sites including, but not limited to, operating system, access times, browser information (e.g., type, language, and history), settings, and other data about your device that we use to provide the services or as otherwise described in this Policy (" **Device Information** "). 

**Location Information**  
If you use our Site, we may receive your generic location (such as city or neighbourhood). We may use and store this information to provide and improve features of our Sites, for example, to tailor our Sites to provide you more relevant content. 

### How we use your information

We may use your personal information:-

To analyse use of the site; and

To inform you of other services, products and events, provided by SquareMeal, Monomax Ltd or its subsidiaries and

For the following other purposes (including the above being "Purposes"), to: provide you with the services, products, and functionality offered on our Sites and fulfill your requests, including, but not limited to, making reservations, reviewing restaurants, paying for services, and notifying people you add to, or otherwise request to notify of, your restaurant reservations through our Sites; communicate with you about your account or use of our Sites, services, products and/or functionality; to invite you to various events and tastings; to invite you to enter competitions and other user events; respond to, or follow up on, your comments and questions, and otherwise provide customer service; communicate with you about special offers and other marketing communications; operate and improve our Sites, products, services, and functionality; process and deliver contest entries and rewards; authenticate your credit or debit card account information, if applicable; personalise your experience on our Sites, including displaying relevant advertising; provide information, services and products to our customers, including restaurants and their restaurant groups and restaurant affiliates; link or combine with other information we get from third parties to help understand your needs and provide you with better service; perform statistical analysis; protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity; comply with our policies, procedures and legal obligations; and as otherwise consented to by you and as required or permitted by applicable law.

**Electronic Communications**  
Consistent with the above Purposes, we may communicate with you via electronic messages, including email or text message, for example: send you information relating to our products and services, including reservation confirmations and updates, receipts, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages; communicate with you about competitions, offers, promotions, rewards, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by SquareMeal, Monomax Ltd , its subsidiaries, our affiliates, restaurants, and other business partners. We may contact you at the mobile phone number that you provide to us by way of direct dial calls, and text messages in connection with the above Purposes. 

**Data Controller and Data Processor**  
We act as the data controller of your personal information. We are not responsible for any restaurant's use of information for which it is an owner or controller. To learn more about how a restaurant may use such personal information, you should review its privacy notice. Whilst we also act as data processor of your personal information we also allow our third party service providers to act as data processors only if this is necessary or reasonably required to supply the Services. 

**Retention of personal Information**  
We will retain your information for the period necessary to fulfill the Purposes outlined in this Policy and as otherwise needed to comply with applicable law and internal company policies. 

### Sharing your personal Information

We will share your information with our subsidiaries, affiliates and third party service providers only if this is necessary or reasonably required to provide the Services. Such third party service providers are not entitled to use your information for their own purposes. Some of our third party service providers may be located outside of the United Kingdom, including in countries where data protection laws might not exist or be of a lower standard than the EU. If you wish to opt out of this, please email [privacy@squaremeal.co.uk](mailto:privacy@squaremeal.co.uk).

**Information shared with restaurants**  
When you make a dining request through our Sites, such as a restaurant reservation or making a payment to a restaurant through our Sites, we automatically provide and share certain categories of your information to the restaurant in order to facilitate your request. For requests to dine, this information may include your name, time and date of visit, party size, your phone number, your dining preferences, guest information, any special requests or comments that you choose to submit (if any), and your email address. Your information is provided to the restaurant, just as it would if you contacted the restaurant directly. If you provide a mobile phone number in connection with your dining request, restaurants may send you text messages regarding your dining request. Some restaurants also require you to provide credit or debit card account information to secure your reservation. 

**Information shared in order to process a card payment**  
To use certain services on our Sites (such as to make reservations at certain restaurants; to make payments to certain restaurants; to buy SquareMeal Restaurant vouchers; and to buy tickets for events), we may require credit or debit card account information. By submitting your credit or debit card account information through our Sites, to the extent permitted by applicable law, you expressly consent to the sharing of your information with restaurants, third-party payment processors, and other third-party service providers (including, but not limited to, vendors who provide fraud detection services to us and other third parties). 

**Information you share socially**  
Our Sites may allow you to connect and share your actions, comments, content, and information publicly or with friends. Our Sites may also allow you to connect with us on, share on, and use third-party platforms, including those on which SquareMeal has a presence. 

Please be mindful of your personal privacy needs and the privacy needs of others as you choose whom to connect with and what to share and make public. We cannot control the privacy or security of information you choose to make public or share with others. Monomax Ltd also does not control the privacy practices of third-party platforms. Please contact those sites and services directly to learn about their privacy practices.

**Other Sharing**  
We do not share your information with third parties other than as described above and as follows: 

We may share your information with our subsidiaries. By visiting or using our Sites or otherwise providing us with your information, you consent to this transfer of your information.

We may share your information with our partners of specific events (such as competitions, users events, reader events, tastings or other events) where you have entered and given your information in order to participate or have attended in person. 

We may share information with third-party vendors, consultants, and other service providers who perform functions on our behalf (e.g., hosting or operating our Sites, data collection, reporting, ad response measurement, site analytics, data analysis, delivering marketing messages and advertisements, processing credit card payments, and providing fraud detection services). We do not authorize these third parties to use your information for purposes other than for which it has been provided, and do not authorize these third parties to disclose that information to unauthorized parties. We require these third parties to maintain appropriate security to protect your information from unauthorized access or processing.

We may disclose or transfer your information to a third party if we sell, transfer, divest, or disclose all or a portion of our business or assets to another company in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, transaction, or proceeding.

We may share aggregate statistical data for the improvement of services offered by our Sites. We may also share aggregated or de-identified information with third parties in our discretion.

### Your Preferences

SquareMeal has an online preference page (" **Preference Centre** ") where you can choose which communications you would like to receive from us.

If you are a registered user and do not want to receive these communications, update your account details at your Preference Centre. Alternatively, you can click on the "unsubscribe" link in the email to link through to your Preference Centre. You will be removed from our lists and won’t receive any communications you decide to opt-out from. If you are not a registered user and do not want to receive this information, email [unsubscribe@squaremeal.co.uk](mailto:unsubscribe@squaremeal.co.uk).

### Protection information

We are committed to protecting your privacy and we implement various security measures in relation to our processing and transfer of personal data. However, the nature of the Internet is such that the data may in some circumstances flow over networks without full security measures and could be accessible to unauthorised persons.

### Cookies

We may use cookies and other technologies while you access the Sites to avoid the need to re-enter details on different occasions and to collect information about your usage and activity on our Sites. Our third-party service providers, advertisers, and/or partners may also place similar technologies on our Sites. The use of these technologies by such third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this Policy, except as required by law.

Advertisements on our site are sometimes provided by another organisation. Our advertising partner will serve ads that it believes are most likely to be of interest to you, based on information about your visit to this and other websites (this information is anonymous in that it does not include your name, street address, e-mail address or telephone number). In order to do this, our advertising partner may need to place a cookie (a small text file) on your computer.

If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may change the settings on your computer or browser accordingly.

### International transfers

Please note that, from time to time, we may transfer your personal data for internal business purposes to locations outside the European Economic Area, some of which may have different data protection laws to the UK, or no data protection laws. Note that in respect of information transmitted to the US, we shall only transmit such information to entities that comply with suitable policies.

### Links to other websites

Our Sites may contain links to other websites or services that are not owned or controlled by Monomax Ltd , including links to websites of restaurants and our advertisers, sponsors, and partners. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of these sites. Your use of third parties' websites linked to our Sites is at your own risk, so we encourage you to be aware when you leave our Sites and to read the privacy statements applicable on those sites. This Policy does not apply to information collected on third parties’ sites.

### Changes to this Policy

We may change this Policy at any time and such changes will take effect from the date and time the revised Policy is available on the site and your continued use of the site shall constitute acceptance. Please refer to this Policy each time you submit your personal information. You are free to decide whether or not to accept a modified version of this Policy, but accepting this Policy, as modified, is required for you to continue using our Sites. If you do not agree to the terms of this Policy or any modified version of this Policy, your sole recourse is to terminate your use of our Sites. All personal information is processed by us in accordance with data protection legislation applicable in the UK.

### Updating your information

If you have registered with squaremeal.co.uk and you wish to make changes to your personal information at any time, edit your account details. You may also contact us as detailed in the Contact us section, below.

### Your right to access the information

You have the right to access the information that Monomax Ltd holds about you in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. In order to do this, please make a written application to the Data Protection Officer, at the address provided below. Monomax Ltd may require you to provide verification of your identity and to pay an administrative fee (which is currently £10) to provide a copy of the information that it holds. Please note that in certain circumstances Monomax Ltd may withhold access to your information where it has the right to do so under current data protection legislation.

### Contact us

If you have any questions about this Policy or information we have collected about you, please contact us by email at [privacy@squaremeal.co.uk](mailto:privacy@squaremeal.co.uk) or by mail at:

Monomax Limited  
Quadrant House  
250 Kennington Lane  
London SE11 5RD 

**Last Updated : May 1st, 2018**
